<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>My First Triathlon: Graduation Is Not the End, But a New Beginning</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/16/My-First-Triathlon-Graduation-Is-Not-the-End-But-a-New-Beginning/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/16/My-First-Triathlon-Graduation-Is-Not-the-End-But-a-New-Beginning/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="🏅-My-First-Triathlon-Graduation-Is-Not-the-End-But-a-New-Beginning"><a href="#🏅-My-First-Triathlon-Graduation-Is-Not-the-End-But-a-New-Beginning" class="headerlink" title="🏅 My First Triathlon: Graduation Is Not the End, But a New Beginning"></a>🏅 My First Triathlon: Graduation Is Not the End, But a New Beginning</h1><p><em>by Ezra Wu | Jul 4, 2025</em></p><p>That was a <strong>1 hour and 40 minutes</strong> challenge.</p><p>I participated in a triathlon for the first time in my life—running and rafting—on a hilly course. Halfway through, my body refused to cooperate, leaving only my willpower to push me forward.</p><p>Along the way, there were thoughtful aid stations with slices of watermelon. It was so hot and I was so thirsty that I accidentally ate too much, and ended up “vomiting watermelon juice” while running—both embarrassing and funny. Every step felt like a battle with myself, and in my mind, I even imagined my loved one running ahead, just to keep me going.</p><p>I was exhausted—<strong>so tired</strong>—but I wanted to prove that I could push through.</p><hr><h2 id="🏆-The-Ceremony-of-My-“First-Time”-Was-Not-in-a-Hall-But-in-the-Wilderness"><a href="#🏆-The-Ceremony-of-My-“First-Time”-Was-Not-in-a-Hall-But-in-the-Wilderness" class="headerlink" title="🏆 The Ceremony of My “First Time” Was Not in a Hall, But in the Wilderness"></a>🏆 The Ceremony of My “First Time” Was Not in a Hall, But in the Wilderness</h2><p><img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:640/format:webp/0*zV3QvATrEMwu3AyP" alt="Watermelon Aid Station"></p><p>Crossing the finish line, I felt an incredible rush.</p><p>Sweat, vomiting, watermelon, imagination, persistence, acceleration—all mixed together in a way words can’t describe. All I knew was: <strong>I made it. I finished.</strong></p><p>The rafting afterward was even more exhilarating. The waves of Xiuguluan River, the sunshine, and the staff’s playful splashes instantly pulled me out of my fatigue. Laughter echoed everywhere, and I met some new friends who were just as passionate, brave, and willing to challenge themselves.</p><p>At that moment, a thought came to me:</p><blockquote><p>“This is my university graduation ceremony.”</p></blockquote><p>Not sitting in an auditorium, listening to someone give a speech—but pushing my limits, facing the unknown, and finishing with a smile.</p><hr><h2 id="🌱-Growing-Up-Is-Not-Scary-What’s-Scary-Is-Not-Writing-Your-Own-Story"><a href="#🌱-Growing-Up-Is-Not-Scary-What’s-Scary-Is-Not-Writing-Your-Own-Story" class="headerlink" title="🌱 Growing Up Is Not Scary; What’s Scary Is Not Writing Your Own Story"></a>🌱 Growing Up Is Not Scary; What’s Scary Is Not Writing Your Own Story</h2><p><img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:640/format:webp/0*3iTN0d-Hv-0nyIdS" alt="Rafting Adventure"></p><p>After finishing the duathlon, I no longer feared growing up.</p><p>Because I realized that true “growing up” is not measured by age, but by whether we can bravely face challenges, get through low points, and then, on a sunny afternoon, smile at ourselves.</p><p>There are many more races and countless unpredictable adventures ahead, but I am ready to continue writing this journey—one page at a time.</p><p>Let every challenge become the most passionate chapter in my story.</p><hr><h2 id="📸-More-Images"><a href="#📸-More-Images" class="headerlink" title="📸 More Images"></a>📸 More Images</h2><p><img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:640/format:webp/0*H7UVBlmR24r4LMy_" alt="Race Start"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>triathlon</tag>
      
      <tag>adventure</tag>
      
      <tag>personal</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Coolest Thing I&#39;ve Ever Done</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/16/The-Coolest-Thing-I-ve-Ever-Done/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/16/The-Coolest-Thing-I-ve-Ever-Done/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="The-Coolest-Thing-I’ve-Ever-Done-Building-an-AI-Learning-Tool-for-Visually-Impaired-Children"><a href="#The-Coolest-Thing-I’ve-Ever-Done-Building-an-AI-Learning-Tool-for-Visually-Impaired-Children" class="headerlink" title="The Coolest Thing I’ve Ever Done: Building an AI Learning Tool for Visually Impaired Children"></a>The Coolest Thing I’ve Ever Done: Building an AI Learning Tool for Visually Impaired Children</h1><p><strong>By Ezra Wu | April 5, 2025</strong></p><hr><h2 id="The-Beginning-A-Spark-of-an-Idea"><a href="#The-Beginning-A-Spark-of-an-Idea" class="headerlink" title="The Beginning: A Spark of an Idea"></a>The Beginning: A Spark of an Idea</h2><p>In October 2024, I saw the announcement for the <strong>Microsoft Imagine Cup</strong>. A thought flashed through my mind: <em>What if we could really use technology to change the world?</em>  </p><p>The first prize was a whopping $100,000, but more than the money, what drew me in was the possibility of <strong>making a real impact</strong>.</p><hr><h2 id="How-It-Started-One-Phone-Call"><a href="#How-It-Started-One-Phone-Call" class="headerlink" title="How It Started: One Phone Call"></a>How It Started: One Phone Call</h2><p><img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:640/format:webp/1*AoUwtMLVghE4mYRv2BkWtw.png" alt="Team brainstorming session"></p><p>My first teammate was a high school student I met during a competition in China. We weren’t close at first, but we shared a common interest: <strong>creating something meaningful for society</strong>.  </p><p>We decided to focus on the visually impaired. Our initial idea was to develop a smart cane. But we didn’t want to guess the users’ needs—we wanted to understand them deeply.  </p><p>We started by calling <strong>50 blind massage centers</strong> in Yunlin and Changhua. These interviews gave us a glimpse into the lives of visually impaired people, but we wanted to go further.  </p><p>With the help of a school professor, we were able to visit <strong>Huiming Blind School</strong>. There, teachers and students revealed the biggest pain point in Taiwan’s special education: <strong>learning resources are expensive and limited</strong>.</p><hr><h2 id="A-Global-Team"><a href="#A-Global-Team" class="headerlink" title="A Global Team"></a>A Global Team</h2><p>Interestingly, our project evolved into a <strong>truly international collaboration</strong>.  </p><p>Our team spread across <strong>South Africa, Australia, India, Vietnam, and China</strong>, meeting weekly on Discord. Time zones, languages, cultures—every aspect was a challenge, but it made the journey unique.  </p><p>I vividly remember our <strong>third full-team meeting</strong>. I was sipping Jin Xuan tea, thinking: <em>Wow, I’m actually discussing how to help blind children with friends from all over the world.</em>  </p><p>The pressure was intense, but the excitement and sense of mission kept me going.</p><hr><h2 id="What-We-Built"><a href="#What-We-Built" class="headerlink" title="What We Built"></a>What We Built</h2><p>We decided to develop an <strong>AI learning platform specifically for low-vision children</strong>. Think of it as a Notebook LM for the visually impaired, focused on <strong>auditory learning</strong> and <strong>personalized instruction</strong>.  </p><p>The AI assistant can <strong>read content aloud, answer questions, generate quizzes</strong>, and even <strong>identify learning gaps</strong> to provide tailored suggestions.  </p><p>We also built a <strong>content management system</strong> for teachers to create their own lesson databases and track each student’s progress, helping them move forward step by step.</p><hr><h2 id="Struggles-and-Challenges"><a href="#Struggles-and-Challenges" class="headerlink" title="Struggles and Challenges"></a>Struggles and Challenges</h2><p>Reality was far more complicated than our ideal.  </p><p>The Microsoft resources we received ran out in the first month, and we had to cover all cloud costs ourselves. Cross-time-zone meetings were sometimes chill, sometimes high-pressure, often in the middle of the night, which took a toll on our bodies and minds.  </p><p>By early 2025, I was diagnosed with <strong>depression</strong>. I hit rock bottom, constantly asking myself: <em>Should I keep going?</em>  </p><p>But when I thought of the children we interviewed and the laughter, debates, and breakthroughs from our brainstorming sessions, I knew I couldn’t give up.  </p><p>Together, we <strong>built the MVP</strong>. That moment, I genuinely felt: <em>We are unstoppable.</em></p><hr><h2 id="Watch-Our-AI-Project-in-Action"><a href="#Watch-Our-AI-Project-in-Action" class="headerlink" title="Watch Our AI Project in Action"></a>Watch Our AI Project in Action</h2><p>Check out our project demo video on YouTube:</p><iframe width="560" height="315"     src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9P7qIEQanE0"     title="YouTube video player"     frameborder="0"     allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"     allowfullscreen></iframe><hr><h2 id="Afterword-Connection-and-Continuation"><a href="#Afterword-Connection-and-Continuation" class="headerlink" title="Afterword: Connection and Continuation"></a>Afterword: Connection and Continuation</h2><p>Although we didn’t advance in the Imagine Cup, our project is now submitted to the <strong>2025 BCM Social Entrepreneurship Competition</strong>. We are preparing a <strong>second visit to Huiming Blind School</strong> to continue improving the platform.  </p><p>That friend from China still keeps in touch, sharing new tech ideas. Andy from Australia found a new job, yet we still reminisce about the nights we worked together until the early morning.  </p><p>This experience taught me that <strong>projects aren’t about competitions—they’re about the people you want to help</strong>.</p><hr><p><strong>If you ask me the coolest thing I’ve ever done</strong>, I would answer without hesitation:  </p><p><strong>It’s building a tool with friends from around the world, for children who cannot see, that helps them see their future.</strong></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>AI</tag>
      
      <tag>Education</tag>
      
      <tag>SocialImpact</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why I Deleted All My Social Media</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/16/Why-I-Deleted-All-My-Social-Media/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/16/Why-I-Deleted-All-My-Social-Media/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Why-I-Deleted-All-My-Social-Media-Choosing-to-Give-My-Attention-Back-to-Myself"><a href="#Why-I-Deleted-All-My-Social-Media-Choosing-to-Give-My-Attention-Back-to-Myself" class="headerlink" title="Why I Deleted All My Social Media | Choosing to Give My Attention Back to Myself"></a>Why I Deleted All My Social Media | Choosing to Give My Attention Back to Myself</h1><p>Social media drained my focus, my thoughts, and my sense of real connection.<br>It wasn’t until I let it go that I finally found myself again.  </p><p>A few months ago, I deleted all of my social media accounts.<br>No farewell post, no dramatic announcement—just silence. I only kept Gmail as my way of staying in touch.  </p><p>It wasn’t an impulsive decision. It was the result of months of inner struggle, a choice made for healing and for reclaiming my focus.  </p><hr><h2 id="I-Cared-Too-Much-About-People-Who-Didn’t-Care-About-Me"><a href="#I-Cared-Too-Much-About-People-Who-Didn’t-Care-About-Me" class="headerlink" title="I Cared Too Much About People Who Didn’t Care About Me"></a>I Cared Too Much About People Who Didn’t Care About Me</h2><p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1633977264263-3514fb5ca1a2?q=80&w=764&auto=format&fit=crop&ixlib=rb-4.1.0&ixid=M3wxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8fA==" alt="Unsplash image by Gaspar Uhas">  </p><p>At one point, I was spending nearly <strong>eight hours a day</strong> on Instagram.<br>I checked who posted a story, who replied to my messages, who ignored me, whose life looked better than mine.  </p><p>It wasn’t their fault—it was mine.<br>I cared too much about people who never cared back.  </p><p>This <em>over-caring</em> left me mentally exhausted.<br>I thought I was “maintaining connections,” but in reality, I was letting algorithms hijack my attention in exchange for emptiness.  </p><hr><h2 id="I-Asked-Myself-Is-This-Information-Changing-Me"><a href="#I-Asked-Myself-Is-This-Information-Changing-Me" class="headerlink" title="I Asked Myself: Is This Information Changing Me?"></a>I Asked Myself: <em>Is This Information Changing Me?</em></h2><p>One day, I sat down and asked myself:  </p><p>If the information I consume daily shapes my thoughts,<br>then what are these endless scrolls doing to me?  </p><p>The questions piled up:  </p><ul><li>Am I letting my brain be filled with fragments of noise?  </li><li>Am I replacing real thinking with shallow topics?  </li><li>Am I mistaking fake, polished lives for “normal”?  </li><li>Has my way of speaking become restless and hollow because of this?  </li><li>Has my self-image been twisted by the content I consume?</li></ul><p>The answers were terrifying. Almost all of them were <em>yes</em>.  </p><hr><h2 id="Choosing-to-Keep-Only-What-Feeds-Me"><a href="#Choosing-to-Keep-Only-What-Feeds-Me" class="headerlink" title="Choosing to Keep Only What Feeds Me"></a>Choosing to Keep Only What Feeds Me</h2><p>I made a deal with myself: if I’m going to spend one hour each day consuming content, then I must consciously choose what it is.  </p><p>So I divided information into two categories:  </p><p><strong>Worthwhile, nourishing content:</strong>  </p><ul><li>Thoughtful podcasts (knowledge, inspiration)  </li><li>Insightful YouTube channels (documentaries, culture, education)  </li><li>Articles and blogs that share honest perspectives  </li><li>Beautifully crafted games (where design, sound, and story matter)</li></ul><p><strong>Low-quality distractions to avoid:</strong>  </p><ul><li>AI-generated endless short videos  </li><li>“Cotton candy” content that gives dopamine but no depth  </li><li>Shallow Instagram posts of curated lifestyles  </li><li>Empty viral gimmicks with no creativity</li></ul><p>This simple filter redefined what counts as <em>leisure</em> and what is simply <em>wasted time</em>.  </p><hr><h2 id="I-Found-Back-My-Words—and-Myself"><a href="#I-Found-Back-My-Words—and-Myself" class="headerlink" title="I Found Back My Words—and Myself"></a>I Found Back My Words—and Myself</h2><p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1507842217343-583bb7270b66?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&auto=format&fit=crop&w=1600&q=80" alt="Unsplash image by David DINTSH">  </p><p>After deleting social media, I felt lighter.<br>No more notifications to check every minute. No more envy or insecurity from watching others.  </p><p>Instead, I now enjoy deep conversations with two or three people who truly matter. I find joy in books, blogs, writing, learning, and exercising.  </p><p>There was a time when I stopped reading, and my vocabulary shrank until I felt almost speechless.<br>But now, I’ve reclaimed my language, my focus—most importantly, myself.  </p><hr><h2 id="A-Reminder-Your-Attention-Is-Your-Most-Precious-Resource"><a href="#A-Reminder-Your-Attention-Is-Your-Most-Precious-Resource" class="headerlink" title="A Reminder: Your Attention Is Your Most Precious Resource"></a>A Reminder: Your Attention Is Your Most Precious Resource</h2><p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1522205408450-add114ad53fe?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&auto=format&fit=crop&w=1600&q=80" alt="Unsplash image by Lena Taranenko">  </p><p>I’m not saying you should delete all your accounts today.<br>But I do invite you to ask yourself this:  </p><p><strong>“Does what I scroll through every day actually make me better?”</strong>  </p><p>If the answer is no, then maybe it’s time to give your attention—and your life—back to yourself.  </p><hr><h2 id="Q-A-Common-Questions-About-Quitting-Social-Media"><a href="#Q-A-Common-Questions-About-Quitting-Social-Media" class="headerlink" title="Q&amp;A: Common Questions About Quitting Social Media"></a>Q&amp;A: Common Questions About Quitting Social Media</h2><p><strong>Q1: What if I miss something important?</strong><br>Don’t worry. Truly important things will reach you.<br>If the world were collapsing tomorrow, your friends, family, or coworkers wouldn’t rely on Instagram to tell you.  </p><p><strong>Q2: Will my friendships disappear without IG or Facebook?</strong><br>No. Real friendships don’t vanish with a deleted account.<br>Those who care about you will still find you. The ones who don’t? They weren’t truly close to begin with.  </p><p><strong>Q3: How do I stay connected without social media?</strong><br>By reaching out intentionally. I now use Gmail, LINE, or SMS for people who matter. I schedule calls, write emails, or meet in person. These connections feel more real than likes and stories ever did.  </p><p><strong>Q4: Won’t I feel lonely?</strong><br>You’ll feel quiet, not lonely.<br>At first, it’s strange because we’re used to filling every silence with noise. But soon you realize—loneliness isn’t the lack of information, it’s the inability to be with yourself. Once you start reading, writing, exercising, or creating, you’ll find freedom.  </p><p><strong>Q5: Will I miss out on trends or news?</strong><br>Not really. In fact, I’m more focused now. I choose what I consume: newsletters, podcasts, and selected sites. Instead of being force-fed by algorithms, I practice <em>information subtraction</em>. That gives me clarity and control.  </p><hr><p>👉 <em>Your attention is your life. Don’t waste it on things that don’t deserve it.</em>  </p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Birth of Our Metaverse English Club</title>
    <link href="/2024/06/28/The-Birth-of-Our-Metaverse-English-Club/"/>
    <url>/2024/06/28/The-Birth-of-Our-Metaverse-English-Club/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In 2024, I co-founded a club that quickly became one of my favorite projects: the <strong>Metaverse English Research Club</strong>. What makes this club special is its commitment to creating a fun, interactive, and immersive learning environment. We wanted to break the fear often associated with learning English, replacing it with curiosity and joy.</p><p><img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:1100/format:webp/1*wE1tThuwR_9woGiKdj-V7A.png" alt="VR English Club"></p><p>Our approach is playful and innovative. Through <strong>gamified teaching</strong>, <strong>virtual reality (VR) experiences</strong>, and even <strong>board games</strong>, members engage with English in ways that feel natural, tangible, and exciting. Every session is designed so that learning feels less like a task and more like an adventure.</p><p>Working alongside Joseph, we’ve turned the club into more than just a language-learning space. It’s a <strong>mini technological lab</strong>, a place where creativity meets education, and a community built with care and passion. Members don’t just improve their English—they experience it, practice it, and enjoy it in a supportive, vibrant environment.</p><p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/bh20O3e8JAsv2gesROVonTQMcJE-RcUFxpH1srVriqlhm9lGBV7-qnpwPWvGGZKBuzXmjB9LAsqwsHypdRtLp7fK9mjJEo6hfmFR8-dQgt20-Ps5ul_qh8DffHXvhd22366UBuifYsmg13on11mZyUfFfKtPg-zpT2q1di_qlJylFAnptbpzHA=w1280" alt="VR English Club"></p><p>No matter your current level of English, the club offers a chance to <strong>discover the joy of learning</strong>, and to grow continuously in a relaxed and inspiring atmosphere. It’s a small experiment in blending technology, education, and human connection—but one that has left a lasting mark on everyone involved.<br>For more information, visit our club website: <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/metaverse-english-en">Metaverse English Research Club</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>English Learning</tag>
      
      <tag>VR</tag>
      
      <tag>Gamification</tag>
      
      <tag>Metaverse</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
